Arnulfo Israel Ramos Magaña

Full Stack Developer

Guadalajara, Jalisco
341-136-2414
a.israel.ramos.m@gmail.com
linkedin.com/in/israel-ramos
israelramosm.github.io

Summary

I am a Telematics Engineer with over nine years of experience developing web applications using languages such as Javascript/Typescript, Java, and C#. I mainly developed applications using nodejs with frameworks like expresjs and nestjs as the backend and react/redux and svelte as the front end. I also worked with IBM Cloud technologies such as Event Streams, which is based on Kafka, and NoSQL databases. My strengths are problem-solving, technology, communication, and personal development.

Experience

Full Stack Developer

2020-10 - 2024-05

IBM

Responsible for developing and migrating applications to new technologies using frontend frameworks such as react/redux and svelte, as well as backend frameworks such as expressjs and nestjs and working together with IBM cloud technologies and resources.

- Developed a new frontend application using react/redux and expressis to help employees with informational and behavioral issues within the organization.
- Maintenance and support of the frontend application developed in react/redux and expressjs for any errors that may arise for users.
- · Configuration, development, and monitoring of IBM cloud resources used within the applications.
- Lead event-driven microservices development using IBM cloud technologies such as Event Streams built on Kafka to create cases within applications.
- Development of new internal applications using technologies and frameworks such as Svelte for the front end and nestjs for the back end to create specific cases for the IBM business model.

Java Developer 2019-02 - 2020-10

Tata Consultancy Services

Responsible for the development and maintenance of the backend application and the frontend application using Java as the main language.

- · Responsible for maintaining and updating the credit cards and loans area according to client requirements.
- Work with the Learning and Development team within the office to create and develop applications using technologies such as HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, and JQuery. At the same time, create and organize meetings to learn new technologies used within the office and in the company's projects.
- I was part of the office's onboarding team, which followed up, resolved questions, and guided new developers.

Software Engineer

2017-03 - 2018-12

Unosquare

Responsible for developing various applications and projects using different technologies and frameworks such as Angular, React, C# .NET, and .NET Core and devices such as Raspberry Pi for internal and external use

- Developed the company's main page using technologies such as HTML5, Javascript, CSS3, and C# .NET, creating the views, home page, and information pages according to the client's requirements.
- Maintenance and development of the company's open-source projects using technologies such as Angular, React, and Javascript.
- Maintenance and development of private company projects using C# .NET, Raspberry Pi, and .NET Core technologies.

Internship 2016-09 – 2017-03

Unosquare

Preparation and study for Microsoft certification exams 480, 486, and 487.

Education

Telematics Engineer 2013 - 2016

Guadalajara University

Language and Software

English - Intermediate/Advance

Experienced	Basic/Intermediate Knowledge

Javascript Java
Typescript AngularJs
Nodejs JQuery
Nestjs C#

React/Redux ASP.NET
Expressjs .NET Core
IBM Cloud Bootstrap
REST Webpack

Git
HTML5
CSS3
Sass

Certifications

IBM Certified Advocate - Cloud v2	2019-04
Exam 487: Developing Microsoft Azure and Web Services	2017-03
MCSD: App Builder — Certified 2017	2017-03
Exam 486: Developing ASP.NET MVC Web Applications	2017-01
MCSA: Web Applications - Certified 2017	2017-01
Exam 480: Programming in HTML5 with JavaScript and CSS3	2016-11